## **Frank Gaete**

Palm Beach Gardens, FL | frank.gaete1@gmail.com | (631) 512-1111 linkedin.com/in/frankgaete | frankgaete1.github.io/portfolio

Sr. UX Design & Strategy / Product Design

Versatile UX/UI design leader with proven success driving the creative vision, research, and end-to-end delivery of human-centered customer experiences. Collaborates with product, engineering, and development teams to simplify complex workflows and align best practices with larger business goals, delivering intuitive, practical solutions to real-world problems.

#### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

User-Centered Design Leadership | Cross-Functional Collaboration | Design System Optimization | Multi-Method UX Research
User Journey Mapping | Accessibility & Usability Standards | Agile Methodologies | Training & Mentorship

Tools & Technologies: Figma | Adobe XD | UXPin | Agile | Jira | Confluence | HTML & CSS

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## SENIOR UX DESIGNER - CREDIT CARD GROUP | TD Bank

Aug 2021 - present, remote office

Optimized user journeys across the company's personal and business banking digital payments ecosystem, refining processes alongside cross-functional stakeholders to elevate digital product development standards and contribute to a unified customer experience across responsive browser and native mobile platforms.

- Lead responsive design and usability prototypes, align native mobile design, and contribute in usability testing for continuous user-friendly optimization of Payment Center product, prioritizing the development of simplified workflows and intuitive, self-serve features to ensure its rapid adoption across user segments.
- Initiated the design development of a new self-service Balance Transfer Calculator feature, clarifying design requirements and customer needs through competitor analysis, creative collaboration and usability testing.

#### SENIOR UX DESIGNER & RESEARCH | NextEra Energy

Jan 2020 – Jul 2021, Jupiter, FL | remote office

Guided the end-to-end redesign of several internal nuclear power plant maintenance applications, spearheading multi-method research studies informing overarching design recommendations and enhancing the functionality of regional plants supplying energy to nearly 2.3 million homes and businesses.

• Collaborated on the design of a single sign-on platform improving security and user accessibility across a suite of internal tools, facilitating multiple usability workshops to understand existing pain points and prioritize tasks across teams.

### **SENIOR UX ARCHITECT | Clever Devices**

Sep 2017 - Dec 2019, Woodbury NY

Established and refined design standards, processes and methodologies informing the design and delivery of scalable interfaces and experiences, partnering with cross-functional teams to ensure design consistency across desktop, responsive web, and mobile products to elevate the capabilities of major mass transit clients.

- Championed a consistent UX research strategy across complex projects, defining workflows, style guides, and asset libraries to influence the re-design of multiple product offerings.
- Updated the interface design of the New Orleans Regional Transit Authority's digital route displays, leading the assessment of the system's existing design framework to enhance all stages of creative planning and delivery.

#### **UI/UX DIRECTOR | Valiant Solutions** (now Trackforce)

Jul 2016 – Feb 2017, Woodbury NY

Drove the re-design of the human capital management company's UI/UX design and established a UX research framework, leveraging client insights to build unified user centered designs aligned with business requirements and industry standards enabling the brand's re-launch and eventual acquisition

**UX/UI DESIGN LEAD – INVESTOR COMMUNICATION SOLUTIONS | Broadridge** Apr 04/2011 – Jul 2016, | Edgewood, NY Standardized UI/UX design best practices used to guide the end-to-end development of various desktop and mobile financial applications. Built and led a team of 10 designer/developers that consistently supported and exceeded expectations for product development, browser integration, responsive web design, and user accessibility. Oversaw the design of a first-of-its-kind Investor Communication Portal, strengthening the firm's relationships with several large financial institution clients while saving hundreds of thousands of dollars in annual revenue.

Previous web design & administration experience is available upon request.

# **EDUCATION & TRAINING**

- Bachelor of Arts, Social Science | Adelphi University, Garden City NY
- Internet Architecture | Hofstra University, Uniondale NY
- Client/Server systems | Dowling College, Oakdale NY
- Sergeant | US Army Reserve